https://www.rmhcincinnati.org/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
Ronald McDonald House Charities (RMHC) of Greater Cincinnati respects the sensitive nature of private information that may be shared with us online or offline. This Privacy Policy explains how we collect and use information about our visitors, donors, families and supporters, both on and offline. By visiting www.rmhcincinnati.org or sharing personal information with Ronald McDonald House Charities of Greater Cincinnati via mail, phone, or other means, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.
Questions about this policy may be directed to info@rmhcincinnati.org or 341 Erkenbrecher Avenue, Cincinnati, OH 45229.
Types of Information Collected
Our website provides a convenient way for you to access our services and learn about important RMHC of Greater Cincinnati news and opportunities. We collect information about our online visitors directly from our visitors and indirectly from other companies that provide data to us. We use this information to communicate with our supporters and guest families and to process their transactions. We do not sell it to other organizations.
RMHC of Greater Cincinnati may gather personal information, which is information that is linked to a specific, identifiable individual (such as first and last name, home address, email address, phone number, etc.) (“Personal Information”). RMHC of Greater Cincinnati gathers personal information as it relates to the transaction being performed. For example, to sign up for our e-newsletter, you will be asked to provide your name and email address. Families registering to stay at our House will be asked to provide contact details as well as information related to the care of their children. Donors will be asked for standard credit card information so that the donation can be processed. When you supply information about yourself for a specific purpose, we only use that information for that purpose.
We and any third-party service providers (including any analytics providers or third-party content providers, such as our family registration system), may use a variety of “cookies,” pixels, web beacons and other technologies that collect certain information about your use of our site whenever you visit or interact with it. This may include the browser and operating system you are using, the search terms you used that led you to our site, all of the areas that you visit within our site, and other information. We may use this information for a variety of purposes, including enhancing or otherwise improving the site and our services. The information we collect is generally non-identifying, but if we associate it with you as a specific and identifiable person, we will treat it as Personal Information.
How We Use the Information Collected
We use the information that you supply to us specifically for the purpose that you requested. For example, if you would like to make a donation, we will use the personal information you provide to us to process that donation. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete that order.
You can register on our website to receive news and information from us via email. If you have not specifically elected to receive such materials, we will not send them to you.
RMHC of Greater Cincinnati does not sell, rent or give away our donors’ personally identifiable information with any other entity, except as described below. We do not send mailings to our donors on behalf of other organizations.
On occasion, RMHC of Greater Cincinnati may share your information with our vendors and other partners. For example, we share information with vendors that help us manage data and direct response initiatives. These vendors are bound by strict confidentiality rules and permitted to use the information only to support RMHC of Greater Cincinnati operations. We also disclose information as required by law.
Security and Payment Processing
We use a variety of security measures to protect your data. Personally identifiable information is stored on our server and is not publicly accessible. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online and offline. When we work with other companies to process credit card transactions, those companies also use encryption and other appropriate security measures.
No system can be guaranteed 100% secure, so we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information that you transmit to us, or that we transmit to you, or guarantee that it will be free from any unauthorized access by third parties. However, we are always working to maintain up-to-date and appropriate security mechanisms.
Information Sharing
We may share non-personal information, such as usage information and aggregated user statistics, with third parties at our discretion. RMHC of Greater Cincinnati does not sell or share personal information with unaffiliated third parties for their direct marketing purposes. We may share the information we have collected about you (including personal information): (i) as disclosed at the time you provide your information, (ii) with your consent (iii) as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, or (iv) in the following circumstances:
Third Parties Providing Services on our Behalf
Companies may be engaged by RMHC of Greater Cincinnati to perform a variety of functions, such as assisting with donation collection, providing technical services for our internet sites, etc. Such companies may have access to personal information if needed to perform certain functions. However, these companies may use such personal information only for the purpose of performing that function and may not use it for any other purpose.
Administrative and Legal Reasons
RMHC of Greater Cincinnati reserves the right to use or disclose any information (including personal information) as needed to satisfy any law, regulation or legal request, to protect the integrity of the site; to fulfill your requests; to cooperate in any law enforcement investigation or an investigation on to a public safety matter, to protect and defend the legal rights or property of RMHC of Greater Cincinnati; our site or its users, or any other party; or in an emergency, to protect the health and safety of our users or the general public.
Business Transfers & Transitions
In the event RMHC goes through a transition (such as a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy or sale of all or a portion of its assets, including, without limitation, during the course of any due diligence process), your Personal Information will likely be among the assets transferred. By providing your Personal Information, you agree that we may transfer such information to the acquiring entity without your further consent.
Links to Other Sites
This website may contain links to other web sites. Please note that when you click on one of the links, you are entering another site and our privacy policy will no longer apply.
Users Residing Outside of the United States and Consent to Transfer
This website is operated in the United States. If you are located in another jurisdiction, please be aware that information you provide to us will be transferred to and processed in the United States. By using the site or providing us with any information, you consent to this transfer, processing and storage of your information in the United States, a jurisdiction in which the privacy laws may not be as comprehensive as those in the country where you reside or are a citizen.
Access
You are in control of all personal information you provide to us online or offline. If at any time you would like to correct the personal information we have about you or if you would like to change your preferences for contacts from us, you can let us know by contacting Shawnie Dukes at sdukes@rmhouse.org or 513-559-4622.
Changes to our Privacy Policy
Changing business practices and circumstances may require that we make changes to this privacy policy from time to time. We will notify you of material changes by posting the changed or modified Privacy Policy on our site. Any changes will be effective immediately upon the posting of the revised Privacy Policy unless otherwise specified and your continued use of the site after the effective date of the revised Privacy Policy will continue your consent to those changes. Rest assured, however, that unless we obtain your consent, any changes will not alter how we handle previously collected information.
Contact Us
Adopt a Room
Name*
First
Last
Phone*Email*
MessageCAPTCHA
X
This site uses cookies and has essential privacy policies.
Find out more about our policies.Okay, thanks
